what did I really lose that day?
ano hi honto ni ushinatta monotte nan dattakke
for the life of me I can't remember
tou ni wasureteshimatta yo
we slowly lost sight of each other in the twilight
yuugure de futari sukoshizutsu mienakunatteitte
and yet we're stuck here unable to go home
sore nanoni bokura kaerezu ni ita
weak, frail souls lost in the world
dokoka ni kowaresou na moroi kokoro
we act strong to hide their fragility
tsuyogaru kotoba de ootte kakushiteru
hide their fragility
ootte kakushiteru
so farewell, but even forced apart
sayonara aenakunattatte
our stories go on
bokura wa tsuzuki ga aru kara
even in a world without you, I run
kimi no inai sekai datte hashiru yo
to someday get past the pain
itsuka no itami mo koete
Decryption
Hidden Leaf Intel Division
((フカサク : 最初は自来也ちゃんも
情報集めが目的で➡
Initially, Jiraiya-chan's purpose
was to gather intelligence.
It appears he never intended
to battle Pain.
ペインと戦うつもりは
なかったようじゃ。
But Pain's abilities far exceeded
his imagination.
じゃけど ペインの能力は
想像をはるかに超えとった。
あの男の能力が わからん以上➡
Unless we knew the scope
of his powers,
no one would ever be able
to defeat Pain.
何度 戦うても
誰も勝てりゃあせん。
自来也ちゃんは無理をしてのう。
Jiraiya-chan went beyond his own limits,
and almost managed to
uncover Pain's secrets.
ペインの能力の正体を もう少しで
暴けるところまでいったんじゃ。
自来也ちゃんじゃなけりゃ
そこまでも無理じゃった。
No one but Jiraiya-chan
could have gotten as far.
じゃけんじゃ 逃げようと思うたら
逃げられたのに➡
On top of that...
He could have escaped if he chose to.
Instead he sacrificed his life
to leave this coded message.
命と引き換えに
この暗号を残した。
He entrusted the rest to you all.
(お前らに あとを託したんじゃ))
This frog supposedly contains
a captured Hidden Rain Ninja.
(綱手)このカエルの中に➡
雨隠れの忍を
１人 拘束しているそうだ。
We received prior notice
from Jiraiya-sama.
(イビキ)自来也様から 前もって
話は受けておりました。
Now, grow.
では 大きくなってくれ。
Be as rough as you need to be.
少々 手荒でもかまわん。
Get everything you can from him!
すべてを聞き出せ！
そのつもりです。
I intend to.
AUTOPSY ROOM
SHIZUNE
OYONE
KUMADORI
This is one of the three crucial sources
of data Jiraiya-sama left us.
(シズネ)自来也様が残された➡
３つの情報のうちの
大切な１つです。
We must learn everything
we can from it.
(シズネ)何がなんでも
手がかりを見つけますよ。
- Yes, Ma'am!
さあ 始めます。
All right. Let's begin.
You haven't said a word.
You see something, right?
(シカマル)ずっと黙ったままだがよ。
なんか あんだろ？
(ナルト)う～ん。
I talked to the Fifth
and Kakashi-sensei,
五代目や カカシ先生に
あたってみたが➡
but neither of them had any clue.
何も知らなかった。
That means Jiraiya-sama probably
left this message with you in mind.
つまり 自来也様は お前に宛てて
暗号を残した気がするんだ。
No, I'm positive he did.
いや そうに違いない。
何か… 何か絶対にあるはずだ。
There's got to be something there.
If anything pops up in your mind,
tell us.
(シホ)少しでも
気になることがあったら➡
言ってみてください。 いきなり➡
We're not asking you to
instantly decode the message.
暗号を解読しろだなんて
言いませんから。
う～ん… 見たときから➡
There is one thing that's been
bothering me since I first saw this.
気になることはあったけど。
なんだ？
What is it?
Well...
うん なんで数字ばっかのなかに➡
There's all these numbers.
So what's with this
one katakana letter?
一文字だけ カタカナが
入ってんのかなと思ってさ。
Huh?
はぁ？
カタカナ？
Katakana?
Where do you see that?
どこに そんなもん…。
ほら ここ。
Right here.
What are you talking about?
Isn't that the number "9"?
どこがだよ？
そりゃ 数字の９だろ？
That's what I thought at first...
オレも最初は そう思ったけどよ。
But this is not the number "9".
これってば 数字の９じゃなくて
カタカナのタだってばよ。
It's the katakana letter "ta".
What?
う～ん そう言われりゃ➡
Well, I guess you could
look at it that way.
そう見えなくもねえけどよ
少し強引だろ。
But I think that's a big stretch.
《もしかして…》
I wonder...
Uzumaki-kun, what made you think
this nine was the katakana letter "ta"?
うずまき君 ぶっちゃけ
どうして この９を➡
カタカナのタだと思ったんですか？
Well... Pervy Sage was writing books
all the time...
ああ エロ仙人てば
ずっと本 書いててさ…。
He was an author, after all.
一応 作家だし。 んで オレは
ずっと一緒に旅してたから➡
And I traveled all over with him.
He always made me read
his handwritten drafts,
手書きのやつを
ムリヤリ読まされていたんだよ。
and asked what I thought about them.
感想を言えってさ。
おもしろくはねえんだけど…。
They were really boring though...
((ふぁ～。
What the hell?
なんだ？
(９クティクスって？))
What's "Nine-ctics"?
And whenever there was
the letter "ta," it was hard to read
で タの文字が出てきたとき
読みづらくってさ。
because it would look
like the number nine.
なにしろ 数字の９みたいに
見えっから。
I see... A penmanship quirk!
そうか 手癖！
That was his habit, huh?
癖字ってわけか。
So what you're saying is...
つまり こうか。
When writing the katakana "ta",
自来也様は カタカナのタを書くとき
１画目を短く書く癖があって➡
Jiraiya-sama had a habit of
shortening his first stroke.
So the first and third strokes
get connected.
１画目のおしりに
３画目がくっついてしまう。
And since he rounds
his second stroke,
それに ２画目が丸くなるから➡
it looks like the number nine.
それで タが９に見えてしまう。
Found it.
ありました。 え～と…。
Let's see...
This is a sample of
Jiraiya-sama's writing.
これが 自来也様の筆跡です。
It's the same!
(シカマル)同じだ！
Jiraiya-sama knew that
Naruto-kun would remember
自来也様は カタカナのタを➡
数字の９のように
書いてしまう癖を➡
his habit of writing the katakana "ta"
like the number nine.
ナルト君なら見抜けると思った。
Frankly, this was the common link
between Jiraiya-sama and Uzumaki-kun.
ぶっちゃけ それが➡
自来也様と うずまき君の
共通のカギだったんですよ！
Why didn't you mention such
an important thing sooner?!
なんで そんな大事なことを➡
気づいた時点で
さっさと言わねえんだよ!?
Well, what's the big deal about
knowing that it's the letter "ta"?
だって タってわかったからって
それが なんだってばよ？
That's it!
そうか それだ！
お前が
自来也様の原稿を読んだとき➡
It's when you were reading
Jiraiya-sama's manuscript
that you found out about
his writing habit.
自来也様は お前が
自分の癖を知ったと思った。
Then the code refers to that
book you were reading!
なら 暗号は
お前が言ってた その本だ！
本？
Book?
That's it, Shikamaru!
そ… それです シカマルさん！
そのとおり ぶっちゃけ➡
Right! Frankly, Jiraiya-sama's book
must contain a hint.
自来也様の本に
ヒントが隠されていると思います。
数字はおそらく 文字の順
行数か何か ページ数とか➡
Those numbers must represent
character numbers, line numbers
or page numbers.
I'm certain they hold the key
to the code.
絶対 このカギは
暗号と関係しています。
Naruto, which book is it?
ナルト その本はどれだ？
え～と イチャイチャ… なんだっけかな。
Umm... Hmm... Make-Out...
What was it?
Well then, how many of
Jiraiya-sama's books have been published?
なら 自来也様が
出版した本って何冊ある？
I'm not sure... Four? Five?
よくわかんねえけど
４～５冊かな？
とりあえず
その本を全部調べるぞ。
Then let's just check all of them!
It's probably this one.
(カカシ)それは
おそらく これのことだ。
(シカマル)『イチャイチャ タクティクス』の…。
MAKE-OUT TACTICS
Make-Out Tactics...
- "Ta"?!
(みんな)タ！
Kakashi-sensei!
カカシ先生！
It's been on my mind,
気になって
こっちへ寄ってみたら➡
so I decided to stop by when
I overheard your voices.
声が聞こえてきてな。
だいたいは聞かせてもらった。
I think I caught most of it.
This is the book you're looking for.
お前たちが探しているのは
この本だろ。
"Make-Out Tactics."
『イチャイチャ タクティクス』… そうだ！
That's right.
That's the one Pervy Sage was
working on during our training.
それが 修業で一緒に旅してた時に
エロ仙人が書いていた本だ。
I see... Only Naruto would've known that.
なるほど ナルトじゃなきゃ
気づけなかったことだ。
So Jiraiya-sama did pass
the key on to Naruto.
やっぱり自来也様は
ナルトに暗号を託してたんだ。
Uh-huh!
This "ta" is the first character
in the code.
この暗号の最初のタの文字。
自来也様が書いた本のなかで➡
Of Jiraiya-sama's books,
this is the only title that begins with "ta."
タが最初にくるのは
これしかない。
When a character is used
in a code,
暗号に
文字が使用されている場合➡
it could signify word placement
or line number,
文字の順や
行数とかもありますが➡
but the established protocol is
to check the page number first.
まずは最初に
ページ数を調べるのが定石です。
So... the numbers separated
by commas
そうですね
点で区切ってある数字は➡
are 31, 8, 106, 7, 207, and 15.
Six sets.
31 ８ 106 ７➡
207 15の６種類。
Meaning there are six pages
worth of information.
つまり ６ページ分の情報。
Let's start with page 31.
まずは31ページ
そこを開いてみてください。
Flip to that page, please.
Page 31...
31ページね… 開いた。
Okay, here it is.
Where do we look next?
で あとは どこを見るの？
In situations like this,
こういう場合 まずは素直に
ページの頭文字を見ます。
we look at the first character
on the page.
Please read the sentence out loud
starting from the top.
頭から一文を読み上げてください。
Wha-?
えっ!?
The truth is that you love me?
Which Is why I will
It's dark now, so
Now hurry up and take my
In one blow
Why do I have to
Your hormones
No one will be here for an hour
do
No... I mean...
いや あの…。
What is it?! Hurry up and read!
なんだってばよ！ いいから
早く読んでくれってばよ！
あ…。
早くしろってばよ！
Hurry it up!
ほ ほ… 本当に➡
"I-I-I... really...
あ あ… 愛してる。
love you."
CIPHER DIVISION
There! We now have all six pages.
はい これで６ページ全部ですね。
どうだった？
Well?
If I read the first characters
of the code in order...
頭文字を暗号の順番どおりに
読んでいくと➡
The-Real-One's-Not-Among-Them...
本 物 葉 意 無 椅
ってことになりますね。
That's what it says.
どういうこと？
わからん。
What does that mean?
I don't know.
We ought to relay this
to Lord Fukasaku.
ここは ガマのフカサク様に
連絡をつけてもらおう。
He fought with Pain,
so he may know something.
ペインと戦った本人なら
何か わかるかもしれない。
Then let's go right away
to the Lady Hokage
なら 五代目にすぐ➡
to ask this Lord Fukasaku to come.
そのフカサク様って人を
呼んでもらって…。
May I come along?
私も ついていっていいですか？
Yeah, please do, Shiho.
あぁ 頼む シホ。
はい！
Yes, sir!
All right! Let's go let Granny know!
よっしゃ！ さっさと
ばあちゃんに連絡だってばよ！
ホンモノハイナイ か。
"The-Real-One's-Not-Among-Them."
どうだ じいちゃん仙人
何か わかったか？
Well, Geezer Sage?! Anything?
((自来也 : あの６人のなかに➡
Of those six, not a single one
reminds me of Nagato.
長門の面影を感じる者は
１人もおりません。
だが 輪廻眼を持っていた長門と
わししか知らぬはずの会話を➡
Yet a completely unrelated Pain
knew of a conversation
that the Rinnegan-bearing Nagato
and I shared alone.
別のペインが知っていた。
(顔は違うが
長門を感じるのは確かです))
The faces are different,
but I definitely sense Nagato in them.
わからん
これだけじゃ漠然としすぎじゃ。
I don't know...
This alone is too vague.
じゃあ 何か思うところは
あるんすね？
But there's something?
ペインのことで わかっとることは
もう話したのう。
I've already told you
what I know about Pain.
死んでも生き返るようなヤツじゃ。
Even if he dies,
he can resurrect himself.
憶測だけでは なんとも言えんし➡
So I can't say just from speculations.
この状態で ペインを相手にするのは
危険じゃ。
Under such conditions,
taking Pain on is too dangerous.
ちゃんと謎を解かにゃいけん。
We must uncover all his secrets first.
他の情報のほうは どうなんです？
検屍と尋問。
What about the other sources
of information?
How are the autopsy and
interrogation coming along?
(サクラ)その２つは
まだ時間がかかるみたい。
It looks like they will take
more time.
かかるって どんくらい？
Like how long?
それはまだ
なんとも 言えないわね。
I can't say.
なんだよ そりゃ！
時間かけてチンタラやってる場合かよ。
Oh, come on!
We can't be wasting time right now!
尋問はともかく 検屍は➡
Interrogation aside,
細胞や組織から検出したものを➡
an autopsy requires minute cell
and tissue analyses!
丁寧に分析解析していくものなの。
どうしたって時間がかかる。
These things take time!
早くても１週間はかかるだろうな。
It'll be a week at the soonest.
そんなに かかんのかよ…。
That long...?
まぁ うずまき君
そんなにガッカリしないで。
Now, Uzumaki...
Don't be so disappointed.
じゃあ この件 どうするんすか？
五代目。
So what should we do, Lady Hokage?
検屍は シズネが担当している。
Shizune is heading up the autopsy...
いつもよりは早いだろうが
待つより他にないな。
It should be quicker than usual.
Still, we have no choice but to wait.
直接 行って
せかしてくるってばよ。
I'll go and make them speed it up.
こらナルト テメエ シズネ先輩のジャマしたら
私が許さないわよ！
Naruto! You get in
Master Shizune's way,
and I'll give you a beating!
エロ仙人の仇は オレが討つ。
I will avenge Pervy Sage!
じっとなんて
してらんねえんだよ。
I can't just sit around doing nothing!
じゃが ナルトちゃんよ
今 暗号が解読できたところで➡
But Naruto-boy...
Even if we decoded the message,
it has nothing to do with you.
お前には何の関係もないじゃろう。
そりゃ どういうことだってばよ？
Just what do you mean by that?!
どっちにしろ 今のお前では
絶対に ペインには勝てりゃあせん。
In any case, at this point,
you couldn't beat Pain.
なんだと!?
なら 何か？
What?!
Tell me. Even Jiraiya-chan
couldn't beat this opponent.
自来也ちゃんが
勝てなかった相手に➡
勝つ自信があるというのか え？
Are you saying you're confident
you can?
それは…。
Well...
今のナルトちゃんじゃあ➡
If you were to fight him now,
you'd die a senseless death.
ペインと戦っても
ムダ死にするだけじゃ。
それじゃあ じいちゃん仙人は➡
Then Geezer Sage,
are you telling me
エロ仙人の仇を
このまま見過ごせってのか！
to forget about avenging
the Pervy Sage?
そんなことは言っとりゃあせん。
No such thing.
ここに呼ばれたのは
ちょうど よかった。
Being asked to come was
quite opportune.
わしも ちょうど
ナルトちゃんを迎えに行こうかと➡
I was planning on coming
to get you, Naruto-boy.
思っとったところ
じゃったからのう。
どうじゃ ナルトちゃん。
How about it, Naruto-boy?
わしのもとで
仙術の修業をせんか？
Want to train in Sage Jutsu
under my guidance?
仙術の修業？
Sage Jutsu training?
なるほど ナルトに仙術
それは いい案です。
I see...
Naruto learning Sage Jutsu.
That is a great plan.
仙術って そんなにすごいのか？
Is Sage Jutsu really that awesome?
ああ。 この里で使えるのは
自来也様だけだった。
Yes. Jiraiya-sama was the only one
capable of using it in this village.
ペインは フカサク様とシマ様を
口寄せしている自来也に勝った。
Pain defeated Jiraiya
who had summoned Lord Fukasaku
and Lady Shima.
それは 今のままでは➡
What that means is...
木ノ葉の里の誰も
ヤツに勝てないことを意味している。
At this point, no one in
the Leaf Village can defeat Pain.
わしも悔しいんじゃ。
I am just as mortified...
弟子である自来也ちゃんの仇は
討ちたい。
I, too, want to avenge the death
of my student Jiraiya-chan.
それをできるのは ナルトちゃん
お前だけじゃと思っとる。
I believe that the only one who
can do that is you, Naruto-boy.
オレが？
Me...?
自来也ちゃんの仇を
討ちたいんじゃろ？
You want to avenge Jiraiya-chan,
don't you?
当たり前だってばよ！
なら ついてこい！
Of course I do!
Then come with me.
妙木山で仙術の修業じゃ。
I'll train you in Sage Jutsu
at Mount Myoboku.
自来也ちゃんに
叩き込んだことを➡
Everything that I drove
into Jiraiya-chan,
全部 ナルトちゃんにも
叩き込んでやる！
I will do the same with you.
それで ホントに
ペインに勝てるんだろうな？
Will it let me win against Pain?!
それは わからん。
ナルトちゃん次第じゃ。
That I can't guarantee.
It all depends on you, Naruto-boy.
ええかの？ 綱手。
もちろんです。
Is that fine with you, Tsunade?
Of course...
ナルト 行ってこい。
Naruto, go.
仙術の修業は
想像以上に厳しいぞ。
Sage Jutsu training is more rigorous
than you can ever imagine.
やるかい？
エロ仙人にも できたことだろ？
Are you up to it?
Pervy Sage did it, right?
だったら オレだって負けねえ。
やってやる！
Then I can't lose to him! I'll do it!
《託された弟子 予言の子か》
An entrusted student...
The Child of Prophecy.
よう言うた！
Nicely said!
じゃあ 行くじゃわい。
Then, let us go.
ナルトちゃん 挨拶せえ。
Naruto-boy, say your goodbyes.
行ってくるってばよ。
シカマル 暗号を頼んだぜ。
I'm off.
I'm counting on you with
the code, Shikamaru.
こっちは気にすんな。
Don't worry about us.
検屍と尋問の結果が出しだい
連絡します。
I will contact you
the moment the results of the autopsy
and interrogation are in.
連絡ガエルを残しておく。
何かあったら ソイツに託せ。
I will leave
the messenger frog behind.
If there's anything,
give it to him.
はい。
Yes sir.
ナルト がんばってね。
おっす！
Good luck, Naruto!
Right!
よっしゃ！ 出発だ！
All right! Let's go!
ところで妙木山って どっち？
By the way,
which way is Mount Myoboku?
大丈夫かしら コイツで…。
Can we really trust this guy?
(フカサク)歩いたら １か月はかかる。
It takes a month to
get there on foot.
迷いの山と呼ばれとって➡
It's also known as
Maze Mountain.
秘密のルートを知らんかったら
絶対にたどり着けん。
If you don't know the secret route,
you won't be able to get there.
行くだけで そんな大変なのか…。
It's hard just to get there, eh?
ナルトちゃんよ。
Naruto-boy...
お前は
すでに ガマとの契約済みじゃ。
You already signed
a binding contract with us toads.
そんな心配はいらん。
There's no need to worry.
あっ それ！
Hey! That's the...
では この子は預かるけんの。
Well then, I'll be borrowing this boy.
よろしくお願いします。
Please take care of him.
でも 心配いらないって…。
消えた！
But what do you mean,
there's no need to worry?
He disappeared?
逆口寄せだ。
へえ。
It's a Reverse Summoning.
Wow...
そちらも頼んだけんの。
Good luck on your end too.
よし 我々も 自来也の残した
情報解読に専念するぞ！
All right!
Let's concentrate on figuring
out the data Jiraiya left us.
了解っす。
Roger.
《大ガマ仙人の予言とやらに
自来也が本を書くと出たこと。
The fact that the Great Lord Elder
prophesied Jiraiya writing those books...
それは この暗号を伝えるための
ものだったのかもしれない。
It may have been intended
to enable him
to eventually leave
the encrypted message.
だとすると その予言とやらは
本当なのかもな。
Meaning the prophecy may all be real.
そして うずまきナルト
まさしく あの子が予言の子か》
In which case, Naruto Uzumaki...
He truly is the Child of Prophecy...
どこだ ここ？
Where... are we?
じいちゃん仙人 ここは？
Geezer Sage...
What is this place?
ガマの国じゃ。
ガマの国？
The Land of Toad.
The Land of Toad?
(ガマ吉)ナルト！
ガマ吉。
Naruto!
Gamakichi!
オレが お前を口寄せしたんじゃ
ナルト。
I summoned you here, Naruto.
なるほど そういうことか。
I see... Is that how?
まずは 修業の前の
腹ごしらえじゃ ついてこい。
Before we train, we must eat.
Come along.
えっ 飯？
Food?!
(シマ)さあ たんと食いんさい。
Now, eat up! I went all out
to prepare this meal!
腕によりをかけて作ったけんね。
ほらほら 遠慮しないで
このイモムシも食ってみんさい。
Now, now... Don't be shy.
Try these caterpillars.
い いただきます。
Th-Thank you...
ぐへ～！
あ～。
そんな姿 見たら
母ちゃん ブチ切れるぞ。
Ma will have a fit if
she sees you like this.
だから ムリして
全部食ったってばよ。
I forced it all down, didn't I?!
まあ 食いもんは➡
When you're hungry,
your belly isn't choosy.
腹が減れば 選り好みもできんし
しぜんに慣れるじゃろ。
You'll get used to it in time.
《その頃には
人間じゃなくなってる気がする》
By that time...
I'll no longer be a human being.
では 早速 修業を始める。
オッス！
Now let's begin your training.
まず わしが教えるのは
忍術ではなく➡
Yes sir!
First of all, I must explain that
what I'm about to teach you
is not ninjutsu, but Sage Jutsu.
仙術だということを
説明しとかなきゃ いけん。
説明って？
いいか。
Explain?
忍術が 内なるエネルギーを
利用するのに対して➡
Listen well...
As opposed to ninjutsu,
where you utilize your own
internal energy,
仙術は 外のエネルギーを
取り込んで利用する。
Sage Jutsu involves taking in
outside energy for your use.
外？ どういうことだ？
Outside? What do you mean?
知っとると思うが 忍術とは
己の内の精神エネルギーと➡
As you're probably aware,
Ninjutsu utilizes chakra that is molded
from one's Mental and Physical Energy.
身体エネルギーを練りこんだ
チャクラを利用するものじゃが。
仙術とは
己の内に練りこんだチャクラに➡
Sage Jutsu involves
taking that internally generated chakra
"NIN"
外からの自然エネルギ-を
更に加え 練りこんで➡
"SAGE"
MENTAL          PHYSICAL
and adding Nature Energy
from the outside,
新たに強いチャクラを作って
利用するもの。
resulting in an even
more powerful chakra.
MENTAL          PHYSICAL          NATURE
これにより 今までの忍術 幻術。
And that leads to all
your ninjutsu, genjutsu,
更には 体術までもが
大幅にパワーアップする。
and even your taijutsu getting
a real power boost.
内からの精神エネルギーと 身体エネルギー
そして 外からの自然エネルギー。
Mental and Physical Energy
within oneself,
and Nature Energy from the outside.
この３つのエネルギーを練りこんだ
チャクラから発動する術や➡
Jutsu and techniques born
from the chakra
created by these three combined energies
is what's known as Sage Jutsu.
技のことを 仙術と呼ぶ。
う～ん。
Hmm...
ようするにじゃな
ソフトクリームのチョコバニラ味に➡
Look at it this way...
If you add mint flavor to
chocolate-vanilla ice cream,
ミント味まで加えたら
さらに うまくなる感じじゃ。
then it tastes even better.
(フカサク)
余計わかりにくいわい ガマ吉。
That makes it more confusing, Gamakichi!
ああ そういうことね！
Oh... I get it!
今ので わかったんかい。
ヘヘッ。 ナルトは こういうヤツじゃ。
You understood that analogy?
That's the kind of guy Naruto is.
その自然エネルギーってのは
ようするに なんだってばよ？
So what's this Nature Energy
really about?
己の外 大気と
大地に存在するエネルギーのことじゃ。
Energy that is external to you.
The energy that exists in
the atmosphere and the terrain.
大気と大地… はあ。
Atmosphere and terrain... Okay...
ようするに 空気と地面じゃ。
あっ そういうこと。
As in, the air and in the ground.
Oh, is that what he meant?
ええい 口ばかりじゃ なんじゃ。
Bah! Enough words. I will show you.
そろそろ やってみせようかいの。
このあたりでええじゃろう。
This should be good enough.
おお さすがフカサク様じゃ。
Wow! Lord Fukasaku is amazing!
どんどん自然エネルギーが
集まってくる。
Look at him gather all
that Nature Energy!
えっ どこ どこ？
Where? Where?!
(ガマ吉)すげえ。
Oh, wow...
うお～！
も 持ち上げた！
H-He lifted it!
ど どうじゃ… これが➡
How about that?
This is the power of
Nature Energy-enhanced Sage Jutsu.
自然のエネルギーを取り込んだ
仙術の力じゃ。
でも 何やったか
わかんなかった。
But I don't know what you did...
ただ じいちゃん仙人が
印をしただけにしか。
I only saw you weave a sign
at the beginning.
そりゃそうじゃ。
Well, naturally.
今のナルトちゃんじゃ
自然エネルギーは感じとれん。
Right now, you're not yet able
to sense Nature Energy, Naruto-boy.
つまり 己に取り込むのも ムリじゃ。
So it's impossible for you to absorb it.
じゃあ どうやって？
Then how do I do it?
自然と一体になるのじゃ。
You must become one with nature!
一体？
Become one...?
ようするに
死ねっちゅうことじゃ。
As in, you have to die.
え？
What?
yesterday, I cut my hair a little
kinou sukoshi kami wo kitta
if I don't say it, I'm sure
iwanakareba kitto
nobody will realise, I guess
daremo kizukanai darou kedo
for a long time
nankagetsu ka bun no
I looked
watashi ga yuka ni
at what fell down on the floor
okkochita no wo mita
I closed my eyes
me wo tojite
and I could hear the sound of rain
kikoete kita ame no oto
even from above the clouds, I'm sure
kumo no ue demo kitto
take out a pair of scissors
hasami mochidashite
we're waiting for the light
hikari wo matteiru
bicycle, bicycle, bicycle, bicycle, bicycle
jitensha jitensha jitensha jitensha jitensha
pedal, pedal, pedal, pedal
koide koide koide koide
pedal, and come on
koideiku yo
right now, right now, right now, right now, right now
imasugu imasugu imasugu imasugu imasugu
bicycle, bicycle
jitensha jitensha
pedal
koide
let's go to see him
ano hito ni ai ni yukou
bicycle, bicycle, bicycle, bicycle, bicycle
jitensha jitensha jitensha jitensha jitensha
pedal, pedal, pedal
koide koide koide
let's go to see him
ano hito ni ai ni yukou
Next Episode
Naruto engages in Sage Jutsu training at Mount Myoboku.
(ガジル)てめえも 時計の部品を
探しにきたのか？
Being much different from ninjutsu,
(サミュエル)君たちとは初対面だね。
Naruto struggles with the training.
名乗っておこうか。
僕は サミュエル。
Fukasaku then reveals what it takes to become a Sage.
(レビィ)あんたが
ナツたちの言ってたエクシード。
Encouraged by the path taken by his master,
そう レギオン隊の頭脳と
呼ばれているのは この僕さ。
Naruto shows he has the guts to never give up.
Next time on Naruto Shippuden: "The First Challenge"
The First Challenge
All right! I'll do this!